马上跪下
On the ground! Now!
弗兰克
Frank?
坐进去吧  孩子
Take a seat, son.
请起立
Please rise.
弗兰克·汉森
Frank Henson,
15年前  宾夕法尼亚联邦将你定罪为
15 years ago, you were convicted by the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania
1998年金伯莉·塔伯特谋杀案的凶手
for the 1998 murder of Kimberly Tolbert.
你被宣判死刑
You were sentenced to death.
因证据不足
This court has found insufficient evidence
本庭无法批准紧急缓刑
to grant an emergency stay.
因此  你的死刑
Thus, your execution will proceed as scheduled
将于三天后的午夜如期执行
at midnight three days from today.
休庭
Court is adjourned.
约翰
John...
真抱歉
I am so sorry.
谢谢你  教授
Thank you, professor.
你们尽力了  我哥哥很感激
You folks did everything you could. I know my brother appreciates it.
弗兰克
Frank...
事情不能就这样结束  我们肯定还能做点什么
This can't be it. There's got to be something more we can do.
我们打算再次检测的化验样本呢  还有...
What about the lab work we were gonna test again, or what about--
阿丽克西斯  我们尽力了
Alexis, we've played every card.
有时好人没法胜诉
Sometimes the good guys don't win.
我不会放弃的
I am not giving up.
你知道为什么吗  因为这是最棒的主意
And you know why? Because it's the best idea ever.
卡塞尔  我不要在太空结婚
Castle, I am not getting married in space.
为什么  我们会是第一对
Why not? We could be the first.
商业太空飞行再过个几年就有了
Commercial space flight is only a couple years away,
而你说过想让婚礼很特别
and you said you wanted it to be special.
是啊  因为
Yes, because when I was a little girl,
我小时候  梦想中的婚礼就是
imagining my wedding day being stuck in a small tin can
被困在一个小锡罐里
with a thousand tons of rocket fuel strapped to my ass
还有一千吨的火箭燃料绑在我屁股上
was exactly what I had in mind.
那我们就意见一致了
Then we agree.
如果你这周末不想去看婚礼场所
If you don't wanna go and look at wedding venues this weekend,
直说就好
then just say so.
我这周末不想去看婚礼场所
I don't wanna go look at wedding venues this weekend.
真可惜
Too bad.
怎么了
What?
没事  只是
Nothing. It's, um,
阿丽克西斯正在忙的课程的短信提醒
text alert on the project Alexis has been working on.
我还以为你们不说话呢
I thought you guys weren't talking.
是的
We're not.
或者说  是她不说
Rather... she isn't.
我侮辱了她男友而已  要判几年刑啊
So I insulted her boyfriend. What's the prison sentence on that?
卡塞尔  给她一些时间  她会想通的
Oh, Castle, just give her some time. She'll get over it.
你太天真了
That's what you think.
她三岁时  我不肯给她买糖
Once when she was 3, I refused to buy her a candy bar.
她屏住呼吸  直到昏了过去
She held her breath until she passed out.
你不知道她有多执拗
You have no idea how determined she can be.
阿丽克西斯  我们按你的要求查看了案件卷宗
Alexis, we went through the case files like you asked.
我得说
I gotta say,
里面没有一点证明他无辜的线索
there's nothing in there that says this guy's innocent.
那我们交给纽约化验室重新检测的
What about the swabs from Kim Tolbert's body
金·塔伯特尸体化验标本呢
that we submitted to the New York trace lab for re-testing?
他们都收到几周了
I mean, they've had them for weeks.
我们每天都在打电话催促
Well, we've been calling every day to move things along,
但那不是我们的辖区
but it's not in our jurisdiction.
你不明白
You don't understand.
除非我们做点什么  否则有人三天后就要死了
A man's going to die in three days unless we do something.
我们很明白  但我们帮不上忙
Oh, we do understand. There's just not much that we can do.
你爸爸呢
What about your dad?
你跟他说过这起案子吗
Have you talked to him about this case?
是啊  也许他能发现别人不能发现的疑点
Yeah, maybe he'll spot something that no one else did.
那...
So...
你来了
you're here.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
但我向你求助
But just because I'm asking
并不代表我俩之间就没事了
doesn't mean things are okay between us.
我还生你的气  好吗
I'm still mad at you, okay?
好吧  出什么事了
Okay. What's up?
我和我的刑法教授在忙活
I've been working on this innocence review case
一起无辜复审案件
with my criminal law professor.
这人因杀了他的邻居  一个高中女孩
This guy is on death row for killing his neighbor--
而被判死刑  但不是他干的
a high school girl-- but he didn't do it,
他们要为此处决他
and they're about to execute him for it.
你怎么知道不是他干的
How do you know he didn't do it?
第一
Well, for one thing,
他四个月前做过肌腱套手术
he had rotator cuff surgery four months before.
他没法挥动杀死被害人的拨火棍
He couldn't have swung the fireplace poker used to kill the victim.
肾上腺素激增时
Well, under the rush of adrenaline,
人们能做到的事能吓你一跳
you'd be surprised what people are capable of.
你的口气和检察官一样
You sound just like the prosecutor.
但还有更多事实
But there's more.
他们在死者后门外的泥土上
They found fresh tire tracks in the dirt
发现了刚压过的轮胎痕迹  自行车的痕迹
outside the victim's back door-- bicycle treads.
而弗兰克没有自行车
And Frank didn't own a bike.
没有  他那时24岁  他修...汽车
No, he was 24 then. He worked on... cars.
等等
Wait.
你怎么知道他的名字的
How do you know his name?
你刚说的
You just said it.
我没有
No. I didn't.
你知道案子的事  怎么知道的
You know about the case. How?
是啊  怎么知道的
Yeah... how?
我一定是在埃斯波西托桌子上看见了文件
I must have seen the file on Esposito's desk.
-你有查探我的情况  -才没有
- You've been checking up on me. - No! No.
有一点吧
Well, a little, yes.
-你真是不可理喻  -忍不住嘛
- You're unbelievable. - Couldn't help it.
你是我女儿  我对你的生活感兴趣
You're my daughter. I'm interested in your life,
但你不回我电话
but you won't return my calls.
那你有什么发现吗
Okay, so did you find anything in the file?
比如有用的线索
Anything that can help?
阿丽克西斯  他有前科
Alexis, he did have priors.
你为什么觉得他是无辜的
What makes you think he's innocent?
因为我了解他  爸
Because I know him, dad.
我和他共度过时光  他不是凶手
I've spent time with him. He's not a killer.
我知道证据对他不利  但他没有杀人
I know what the evidence says, but he didn't do this.
我要你和我一起去宾夕法尼亚州
I need you to come to Pennsylvania with me.
我要你帮我证明
I need you to help me prove it.
没事  我理解
No, come on. I get it.
也就去几天
It would only be for a couple of days,
因为也只剩几天时间了
'cause that's pretty much all the time there is left,
而且我有机会和阿丽克西斯重归于好
and it's a chance for Alexis and me to reconnect.
卡塞尔  你没必要解释
Castle, you don't have to explain.
我们可以改天再看婚礼场所
We can look at venues another day.
你确定你没事吗
You sure you're all right with this?
是啊  她也是我家人  我也关心她
Yes. I mean, she's practically family. I care about her, too.
你真贴心  知道吗
You're pretty great, you know that?
知道  现在去陪你女儿吧
Yeah. Now go spend some time with your daughter.
-谢谢  -祝你好运
- Thanks. - Good luck.
我们很久没有一起自驾游过了
It has been a long time since we have taken a road trip together.
记得我们去阿米什乡村那次吗
Remember the time we went to Amish Country?
最后被那头牛追逐
Ended up getting chased by that cow?
爸  这不是自驾游  不是为了玩乐
Dad, this isn't a road trip, and this isn't about fun.
而是为了在不到70小时内
This is about having less than 70 hours
拯救死刑犯的性命
to save a man from execution.
出发吧
Let's go.
好吧  系好安全带
Right. Fasten your seatbelt.
这一路会很颠簸
Gonna be a bumpy ride.
话说
So...
那谁...
How is, uh...
派怎么样  一切都还好吗
How is Pi? Everything still good?
你为什么要问派的事
Why are you asking about Pi?
我只是想
I... just thought
我们该聊聊
we should chat about--
爸爸  我知道你在干什么
Dad, I know what you're doing.
我在干什么
What am I doing?
你想和我和好
You're trying to bond.
我没有
No, I'm not.
你有  我们几周没说过话了
Yes, you are. We haven't talked in weeks,
所以你现在想把这变成咱俩的事
so now you're trying to make this about us.
不  我没有
No, I wasn't.
我真没有
I wasn't, so...
就算有又怎样  有那么糟糕吗
And what if I was? Would that be so bad?
我以为你只是来办案的
I just thought you were here for the case.
我就是来办案的
I am.
那我们离开到现在
Then how come you haven't asked a single question
你怎么没问过一个与案情有关的问题
about it since we left?
好吧  那介绍下情况吧
Okay. Um... so what do I need to know?
弗兰克·汉森  被告
Frank Henson--the accused.
我们现在要去监狱见他
We're meeting him at the prison.
他是宾夕法尼亚州的一个蓝领
He's pennsylvania blue collar,
高中勉强毕业  不过他很聪明
struggled through high school, but he's smart.
95年  他拿到了汽车修理学位
He earned his automotive mechanic degree in '95.
他这人不太好相处
He's a little rough around the edges,
但他很有爱心
but he's got a good heart.
-好吧  -还有
- Okay. - Oh, and--
这是玛吉
And there's Maggie.
玛吉是谁
Who's maggie?
玛吉·英格拉姆  他的挚爱
Maggie Ingram, the love of his life.
会面时  她也会在场
She'll be at the prison, too.
挚爱
Love of his life?
是监狱里的笔友恋情之类的吗
Is it one of those prison pen pal romance things?
老爸  不是的  他们从高中起就是恋人了
Dad, no. She's his high school sweetheart.
他被捕两周前刚向她求了婚
He proposed to her two weeks before his arrest.
她还留在他身边
And she stayed with him?
她一直都在支持他
She's been by his side the whole time.
每场听证会  每次上诉
Every hearing, every appeal.
就是她一直在给无罪复查机构写信
She's the one who wrote to the innocence review
三年来每周都写  就为了让我们接手
every week for three years to get us involved.
说实话  阿丽克西斯
You know, Alexis, um...
机会不大  你知道的  对吗
Th-this is a long shot. You know that, right?
我是说  最后结果可能不会是你预期的那样
I mean, it may not work out the way you hope.
我只是不希望
I-I just don't wanna...
不希望看到你受伤
Just don't wanna see you hurt.
爸  我认识这些人
Dad, I know these people.
我关心他们
I care about them.
这事已经让我很受伤了
It already hurts.
可以进去了
You're good.
阿丽克西斯
Alexis.
谢天谢地
Thank god.
玛吉  这是我爸爸
Maggie, this is my dad.
-你好  -卡塞尔先生  谢谢你能来
- Hi. - Mr. Castle, thanks for coming.
如果不是阿丽克西斯的电话  我几乎要放弃了
I'd almost given up till Alexis called.
宝贝
Hey, baby.
亲爱的
Hey, sunshine.
什么意思  送别派对吗
So what is this, a going away party?
不  他们是来帮忙的
No. They came back to help.
帮忙  上诉失败  已经结束了  不是吗
Help out? Lost the appeal. It's over, isn't it?
不  还没完
No. It's not over. Not yet.
这位是卡塞尔先生  阿丽克西斯的父亲
This is Mr. Castle, Alexis' father.
幸会  卡塞尔先生
Nice to meet you, mr. Castle.
您女儿是万中无一  您真该感到骄傲
Your girl's one in a million. You should be proud.
我很骄傲
Oh, I am.
你是律师吗
So are you some kind of lawyer?
不是
Oh, no.
那是警察
You a cop?
也不是  我是个悬疑小说家
No. I'm a... mystery writer.
他可不只是小说家
He's more than that.
他帮助纽约警局破获过无数大案
He's helped the N.Y.P.D. crack their biggest cases.
我..  我不想被过分吹嘘
Well, I don't.. I don't wanna oversell it.
你救过死囚犯吗
You ever save a guy on death row?
没有
No.
但我爸爸很擅长发掘事情的真相
But my dad's a genius at uncovering the real story.
弗兰克  我知道这种事你经历过太多次
Frank, I know you've been through this more times
已经超出你的承受范围了  但如果可以
than you can stomach, but if you can...
告诉他那晚发生了什么吧
Tell him what happened that night.
弗兰克
Frank.
当时我在修我的科迈罗
I was working on my Camaro.
那时我除了睡觉  所有时间都花在修它上
I spent every waking hour with it back then.
那天我正在修它的排气系统
That night I was working on the exhaust system
家里的警报响了
my house alarm went off.
我在做焊接  烟雾引发了车库的警报
I was doing some welding, and the smoke set off the garage alarm.
解除密码是stingray7
the code is stingray7.
现在好了  谢谢
It's off now. Thank you.
就在那时  我听到了街对面的尖叫
That's when I heard the screams across the street.
于是我跑过去看发生了什么
I ran over to see what happened.
有人吗
Hello?
没事吧
Is everyone all right?
后门是打开的  于是我走了进去
Back door was open, so I went inside.
她躺在那里
She was lying there.
到处都是血...
The blood was, uh...
不管发生了什么  我都来晚了
Whatever happened, I was too late.
我听到了警笛声  顿时慌了神
I heard the sirens, and I panicked.
我知道这会让人怎么想
I mean, I knew how it would look,
所以我抓了块破布  想擦掉我所有的指纹
so I took a rag and tried to wipe down all my prints,
但是我没时间了
But I ran out of time.
我手上有她的血
I had her blood on me,
还有案底  当然不会有什么好下场
a police record. It... went the way you'd expect.
你的住宅安保公司呢
And what about your home security company?
-他们有你打电话的记录吗  -有
- Did they have a record of your call? - Yes.
但控方争辩说他打完电话仍有足够的时间行凶
But the prosecution argued it still left plenty of time.
你跟金·塔伯特很熟吗
How well did you know Kim Tolbert?
没多熟  她和她妈在那住了几年了
Not that well. I mean, her mom and her lived there a few years,
金跟我调过情
And... Kim'd flirt with me a little bit.
我很友好地回应  仅此而已
I was friendly, but that was it.
他们提交了她的日记作为证物
They entered her diary into record.
上面写她对弗兰克有好感
She wrote that she had a crush on Frank,
于是控方就把弗兰克塑造成了勾引少女的色魔
so the prosecutor made Frank out to be some kind of predator.
你跑进房子的时候  没看到别人吗
And you didn't... see anyone as you ran into the house?
没有  他们一定是在我赶到前都跑了
No. They must have bolted out the back before I got there.
在那之前呢
Well, what about back then?
她跟什么人有过节吗
Anybody she was having a problem with?
莱尔·戈麦斯  金高中时的前男友
Lyle Gomez, Kim's high school ex-boyfriend.
他们的感情非常...轰轰烈烈
They had a very... stormy relationship.
而且  她遇害一周前把他甩了
Plus she dumped him a week before she was killed.
警方找过他吗
Police talk to him?
没必要找他  他们已经抓到我了
Well, they didn't have to. They had me.
卡塞尔先生  我只有三天的命了
Mr. Castle, I've got three days left on God's earth.
我不需要你找出真正的凶手
I don't need you to find the real killer.
只要有人能证明我是无辜的就行了
I just need somebody to prove it wasn't me.
卡塞尔  慢慢说  冷静点
Castle, take it easy. Calm down.
冷静点
Calm down?
你真该看看这些人看我的眼神
You should have seen the way these people looked at me.
好像我是什么救世主一样
Like I'm some kind of savior.
我都不知道他是不是无辜的
I-I don't even know if he's innocent.
我能帮上什么忙
Okay, how can I help?
我都不知道我能不能帮上忙
I don't even know if I can help. I mean...
要是我帮不了怎么办
what if I can't?
阿丽克西斯永远不会原谅我的
Alexis would never forgive me.
尽力就好  卡塞尔  她很爱你
Just do your best, Castle. I mean, she loves you.
而且还有我呢  支持你们
And I'm here... for both of you.
她来了  我得挂了
She's coming. I gotta go.
准备好了吗
Ready to get started?
走吧
Let's go.
这些就是案子的所有相关资料了
This is everything spanning the life of the case.
你的教授起码可以
Well, the least your professor could've done
弄点索引嘛
is throw in some cliffs notes.
关于金的前男友莱尔·戈麦斯  我们有什么线索
So what do we know about this ex-boyfriend of kim's? Lyle Gomez.
他是个大学的橄榄球队员
Uh, was a varsity football player.
跟金有段起起伏伏的恋情
Hot and cold relationship with Kim.
认识他的人都说他脾气很不好
Everyone that knew him said he had a temper.
你们找过他了吗
Do you guys talk to him?
麦克唐纳德教授和辩方律师曾试图找他谈谈
Professor Mcdonald and the defense lawyer tried,
但莱尔说不想再提这事了
But Lyle told them he didn't want to relive it.
说太痛苦了
Said it was too painful.
没有证据表明可能是他干的吗
And there's no evidence that indicates he might have done it?
完全没有
Nothing at all?
尸体周围的地板上这些小东西是什么
What are all these little things on the floor around the body?
吊坠  他们在扭打时扯坏了她的手镯
Charms. They broke off her bracelet during the struggle.
那么在致命一击之前
So before the attack,
可能发生了推搡
there might have been some pushing and shoving.
爱人吵架可能会先这样
Lovers' quarrels can start like that
一不小心就酿成了悲剧
before they turn to something else.
可除了玛吉的说法外
But aside from Maggie's theory,
其他证据联系不到莱尔身上
there's nothing tying Lyle to any of this.
但是...或许你会发现我们所遗漏的
But... maybe you'll see something we missed.
被送交到化验室的
Hey, so that evidence the innocence review
无辜复审报告
submitted to the trace lab--
他们查到什么程度了
how close are they to looking at it?
据我们所知  要花上几周
Well, from what we heard, it's gonna take weeks,
也就是说  来不及
which means they'll never get to it in time.
怎么了
What?
据大家所说
Well, by all accounts,
金是个人见人爱的聪明美女
Kim was a bright and beautiful girl who everyone loved.
没听说她有树敌
She had no enemies to speak of,
也没线索指向弗兰克之外的人
and nothing points to anyone other than Frank.
因为大家觉得没必要怀疑弗兰克之外的人
Because they didn't look at anyone other than Frank.
也许是因为...就是弗兰克干的
Or maybe because... it was Frank.
抱歉  阿丽克西斯  有时...
Look, I'm sorry, Alexis. It's just sometimes--
没关系  如果真是弗兰克  他的动机是什么
Okay, fine. But if it was Frank, what was his motive?
好吧
Right.
你们这些做无辜复审的人就是不懂得放弃  是吗
Wow. You innocence review folks just won't give up, will you?
需要帮忙吗  雷恩警官
Can I help you, officer... "Lane"?
金的谋杀案把这里搅得鸡犬不宁
Kim's murder tore this town apart. I guess, uh,
我们想知道你们都在图什么
we're just wondering what you all are fighting for.
公正
Justice.
Justice?
我们抓到他时  他手里沾满她的鲜血
He had her blood on his hands when they caught him.
他手里拿着
He was holding the shop rag
擦拭过犯罪现场血迹的抹布  你还想要公正
that he used to wipe down the crime scene. You want justice?
让他见上帝去吧
Let him meet his maker.
他们一直这么不友善吗
Has it been like that the whole time?
差不多吧
Pretty much.
好  我们再来过一遍
Okay, let's go over this again.
弗兰克听到叫声  跑了过去
Frank hears a scream. He runs across the way.
他使劲敲门  门锁着
He bangs on the door. It's locked.
他跑到了后门
He runs around the back.
他发现后门开着  就走了进去
He finds the back door open and goes inside.
后门开着  等等
Back door was open. Wait.
案发时间是几月  十一月吗
What time of year was the murder--November?
对  13号  怎么了
Yeah, the 13th. why?
1998年  那晚的温度是...
1998. Temperature that night was...
40度[4摄氏度]
40 degrees.
那又怎样
So?
天气太冷  金不会开着门的
So that's far too cold for Kim to have left the door open.
但据弗兰克所说  门是开着的
Yet according to Frank, it was open,
可以推断凶手另有其人
presumably because someone else committed the crime.
对  可大家都认为他在说谎
Yeah, but everyone thinks he's lying.
没错  可他们看不到的  没人能看到的
Yes, but what they don't see, what no one sees
是我们能证明他是不是在说谎
is that we can prove whether or not he was lying.
快走  我去取车  你付账单
Come on. I'll get the car. You pay the check.
等等  老爸
Wait. Dad?
拜托  老爸  你能告诉我你在干什么吗
Come on, dad. Will you please tell me what you're doing?
如果弗兰克有罪
If Frank is guilty,
那后门就是他开的  那就是说...
then he would have opened the back door, which means...
他会擦拭门把手
He would have wiped down the doorknob
擦掉指纹
to get rid of his fingerprints.
可如果他说的是事实  当时后门
But if he's telling the truth and the back door
的确开着  他就没必要去擦掉
was already open, he wouldn't have needed to wipe it
因为他没碰过
because he never touched it.
那就意味着那晚有其他人去了金家
And that would mean someone else was there that night.
问题是  鉴证组
Question is, did C.S.U.
验过门把手上的指纹了吗
dust that doorknob for fingerprints?
找到了
Here it is.
-验过了  -结果呢
- They did. - And?
结果是...指纹被擦干净了
And... it was wiped clean.
抱歉  亲爱的  他说谎了
Sorry, sweetie. He lied.
-可这完全说不通  -我知道
- But it doesn't make any sense. - I know.
跟你一样  我也希望他是无辜的
I wanted to believe it as much as you.
不  我是指这份报告
No, I mean this report.
上面说后门把手干干净净的
It says the back doorknob was totally clean--
没指纹  什么都没
No prints, no nothing.
所以弗兰克不可能擦拭过
So Frank couldn't have wiped it down.
弗兰克用的抹布上沾满了
The shop rag Frank used was covered in grease
他修车沾上的油  他们在其他地方
from working on his car. They found traces of grease
发现了他擦拭指纹留下的油渍
in other places where he wiped down his prints,
可没有提到门把手上有
but there's no mention of it on the doorknob.
报告上没写
It isn't in the report.
老爸  如果上面没有油渍
Dad, if there wasn't any grease...
那就说明有其他人
Then someone else was there,
在弗兰克到达前擦了门把手
wiped down the doorknob before Frank got there,
把指纹擦掉了
getting rid of their own prints.
还有其他人出现在犯罪现场
Someone else was there that night.
亲爱的  你说得对
Sweetie, you were right.
杀金·塔伯特的不是弗兰克
Someone else killed Kim Tolbert.
是的  教授  我明白
Yes, professor, I understand.
好  再见
Okay. Bye.
-他说什么  -证据不充分
- What'd he say? - It's not enough.
可我们知道了有其他人擦拭了门把手
But we know someone else wiped down the doorknob.
对  可他说我们不能用
Yeah. But he says you can't build a case
不存在的证据来立案
based on evidence that isn't there.
是贝克特
It's Beckett.
进展如何
Hey. Hey, how's it going?
不太理想
I... not--not so good.
我们现在什么线索都抓
We'd be grasping at straws if we had any.
我倒是有条线索给你
Well, I might have one for you.
我昨晚去了化验室
I went to the trace lab last night.
那里人说不会验你案子的证据
Their people wouldn't run your case evidence,
可我另外找了人做
but I found someone else that would.
谁
Who?
我是蕾妮  开扬声器
It's Lanie. Put me on speaker.
好  开了
Yeah. Um... you're on.
阿丽克西斯  你为什么
Alexis, why on earth
偏不肯直接来找我呢
wouldn't you come to me directly?
-蕾妮  我不知道你能  -她说服
- Lanie, I didn't know you could do... - She convinced
实验室的一个朋友在下班后查验证据
a contact at the lab to run evidence after hours.
我们重新检检测了15年前
Now we re-tested every swab taken
金尸体上的每个棉签
from Kim's body 15 years ago.
宾州报告上列出的每样东西
Everything listed in Pennsylvania's report
都出现在我们的报告上
came out in our report,
除了一样东西
with the exception of one thing.
我们发现了微量硝酸铵
We found trace amounts of ammonium nitrate
他们的实验室没发现
that their lab never picked up.
硝酸铵
Ammonium nitrate?
是种氧化剂  常见于
It's an oxidizing agent, commonly found
冰袋  炸药
in cold packs, uh, explosives,
-肥料中  -肥料
- fertilizer. - Fertilizer.
等等
Wait.
莱尔·戈麦斯
Lyle Gomez.
金的前男友  他以前在园艺商店工作
Kim's ex-boyfriend. He used to work at a gardening store.
老爸  是他  所以他才不愿和我们谈话
Dad, it's him. That's why he wouldn't speak with us.
-我们得找他谈谈  -等等
- We have to go talk to him. - Wait a minute.
如果你们觉得其他人有嫌疑
If you guys think someone out there is involved,
那得去找警察
then you need to get ahold of the police.
嗯  我觉得警察不会
Yeah, I don't think the police are gonna be
提供什么帮助
of much help around here.
卡塞尔  如果他是凶手  就很危险
Castle, if he's your killer, he's dangerous.
出了状况我可帮不了你们
I can't help you if something happens.
听着  贝克特   弗兰克·汉森只有两天可活了
Uh, look, Beckett, Frank Henson has two days to live.
这是我们唯一的线索  我们还能怎么做
This is our only lead. What else are we supposed to do?
好了  现在的可能性是  莱尔·戈麦斯
Okay. Now odds are, Lyle Gomez will not
不愿意和我们谈
want to speak with us,
可是我有和这种人打交道的经验
but I've got experience with guys like this,
所以你交给我就行
so you just leave it to me.
他出现了
Oh, there he is.
好吧  出师不利
All right, that does not bode well.
你要去哪里
Oh, oh, whoa. Where you think you're going?
-去找他谈  -阿丽克西斯  当然不行
- To talk to him. - Whoa. Alexis, no. Absolutely not.
他的意图不能更明显了
He just gave us a none-too-subtle hint.
他看着的是你  老爸  他不肯和你谈
He was looking at you, dad. He won't talk to you,
可我能和他沟通
but I can reach him.
这人是个杀人嫌犯
The man is a possible murder suspect.
他不想跟你有任何接触
He won't do anything with you here.
你又凭什么认为
But what makes you even think
他会给你开门
he's gonna open the door to you?
我是个年轻女孩  能让他想起金
I'm a teenage girl. I'll remind him of Kim.
-我才不会  -我没在征求你同意
- No, I'm not-- - I'm not asking for permission.
我会牢牢盯住你的
I'll be watching you like a hawk.
你们这些人  别再来打扰我了
You people need to stay off my property.
我想金看错你了
I guess Kim was wrong about you.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我读了她的日记
I read her diary.
她说你和善  关心人
She said you were kind, caring,
让她觉得安全
made her feel safe.
她还说什么了
What else did she say?
不如你让我进去
How about you let me in?
这些年我没有一天不想念她
Not a day goes by I don't think about her.
你可知爱得越深  心就越疼
You ever been in love so bad, it hurt?
所以你绝口不提当年旧事
Is that why you don't talk about it?
案发时你在哪
Where were you when it happened?
那晚金打电话给我
Kim called me that night.
她让我到绿碧树林接她
She wanted me to pick her up from Jasper Grove.
绿碧树林  那是什么
Jasper Grove? What's that?
农场和树林  在城东  年轻人在那聚会
Farmland and woods, east of town. Kids party there.
她肯定参加了某个聚会  我也很惊讶
She must have gone to one, which surprised me
因为她几乎不喝酒
because she barely ever drank.
但是金和你分手了
But Kim broke up with you, right?
那为什么她要打给你
So why'd she call you?
她说我是她唯一信得过的人
She said I was the only one that she could trust.
-她很不安  -为什么
- She was upset. - About what?
她没说  我以为是有人挑逗了她
She didn't say. I figured somebody hit on her.
总之她让我开车接她回家  我就去了
Anyway, she asked me to drive her home, so I did.
之后呢
What happened then?
我满心希望她打给我
I was hoping that her calling meant
是想和我重燃旧情
that she'd give me another chance.
所以我问她
So I asked
-我能不能进去  -你进去了吗
- if I could come in. - And did you?
她想自己待会
She wanted to be alone.
她说有些事情她必须要做出抉择
She said she had some decisions she needed to make.
于是我决定去借酒浇愁
So I decided I needed to get drunk.
我从商店里偷了几罐啤酒
So I went and I shoplifted a pint of jack,
但是店主抓住了我
but the shop owner caught me.
他让我把他停车场里每一小片垃圾
He made me pick up every single piece of litter
都捡起来  以示惩戒
in his parking lot as punishment.
当我听见警笛的时候
When I heard the sirens,
我还以为店主报了警要抓我
I thought he was arresting me, too.
但那些警车是冲着金家去的
Those sirens were for Kim.
当我赶到她家时  我见到了弗兰克
When I got to her house, I saw Frank.
我在担架上看见了她的遗体
I saw her body on the stretcher.
如果我当初没离开她家去喝酒
If I had just found a way to stay there,
她就不会死了
she'd be alive.
这些你告诉警察了吗
Did you tell this to the police?
他们没问  为何要问  嫌犯已经抓到了
They didn't ask. Why would they? They had the guy.
为什么你认为弗兰克是凶手
Why do you think Frank killed her?
没准他嫉妒了
Maybe he got jealous.
他不喜欢见到她和其他人混在一起
He didn't like seeing her with other guys.
什么其他人
What other guys?
我没问
I didn't ask.
但我知道他们时常去她家
But I know they dropped by her house.
其他的那几个男生
Other boys.
多谢
Thanks.
爸爸  你这是干什么
Dad, what are you doing?!
可能有点反应过度了
I was overreacting, maybe.
你在里面待了好久
You were in there a long time.
我发现了一些线索
And I came away with some leads.
原来金还在和其他人约会
Turns out Kim was seeing other boys.
什么其他人
What other boys?
我们还希望你能告诉我
We were hoping you could tell us.
你家就在她家街对面
You lived across the street from her.
记不记得看见别的男生去金家
Do you remember seeing any other guys go to Kim's house?
-那是十五年前了  -这很重要  弗兰克
- That was 15 years ago. - This is important, Frank.
其中一个或许跟她被害有关
One of them may be involved in her death.
你们就只有这一条线索
That's the only lead you have?
我们也在查那晚金参加的派对
We're also looking into the party Kim went to that night.
我们请纽约警局帮忙查找那晚
We have N.Y.P.D. checking, seeing if
绿碧树林附近有没有
anything was reported in Jasper Grove
和金被害有关的报警
that could connect to her murder.
努力想想你看见去金家的那几个男生
Try to focus on kids you saw at Kim's house.
任何能记起来的细节  发色  开的汽车
Anything you can remember-- hair color, cars they drove,
骑的自行车  不光那一天的  哪天都行
bikes they rode. Not just that day. Any day.
再想想
Try to think.
我想累了
I'm tired of thinking.
实话跟你说  我实在撑不住了
I'm tired all around, to tell you the truth.
弗兰克
Frank.
结束了 阿丽克西斯
It's over, Alexis.
别这么说
Don't say that.
这些年来
All these years...
玛吉一直在打这个官司
Maggie has been leading this charge.
她一直支撑着我
She's been my rock,
现在我得回报她
and now I've gotta be hers.
我余下时日不足两天
I've got less than two days.
要想让她平静接受将要发生的事
To help her make peace with what's about to come,
最不需要的就是虚假的希望
the last thing that she needs is more false hope.
-这不是虚假希望  -这就是  结束了
- This isn't false hope. - It is false hope. It's done.
也许这能扭转整个案情
This could be what turns everything around!
结束了  阿丽克西斯
It's done. Alexis...
狱警
Guard.
对于你的所有努力和尝试
Listen, I appreciate everything you've done,
我十分感激
everything you've tried to do.
但是时候放手了
But it's time to let it go.
爸爸  我们马上就要找到突破口
Dad, we might be on to something.
弗兰克怎么能放弃
How can Frank just give up?
他经历得太多了  这也怨不得他
After what he's been through, I can't blame him.
所以你也要放弃了
So you're giving up, too.
我们会追查每一条可能的线索
Hey, we are gonna follow every possible lead, but...
但不能再去找弗兰克了
we can't go back to Frank,
除非能查出证明他无辜的可靠证据
not until we have solid evidence that he's innocent.
卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
莱恩  关于绿碧森林你查到什么了吗
Hey, Ryan, did you come up with anything on Jasper Grove?
金·塔伯特被害那晚
No police or incident reports
没人报警
from the night that Kim Tolbert died.
不过  我倒是发现绿碧森林那边有问题
However, I did find definite signs of trouble in Jasper Grove.
什么问题
What kind of trouble?
1997年那里的一间农房被没收抵债
A farmhouse there was foreclosed on
一直闲置到1999年
in '97, stood empty till '99.
那年一家年轻住户买下了农房
That's when a young family bought it,
但他们一入住  就全都得了病
but as soon as they moved in, they all got sick.
原因是那地方被有毒化学品污染了
Turns out the place was contaminated with toxic chemicals.
什么化学品
From what?
麻黄碱制品的高浓度残留
Uh, high levels of residue from methamphetamine production,
也许这能解释你们查到的硝酸铵残留
which might explain your ammonium nitrate.
有人用那间农房制冰毒
Someone was using the farmhouse to cook meth?
没错  而且这些人可能是一帮小年轻
Yeah, and it looks like it might have been kids.
为何这么说
What makes you say that?
郡技术员拍下的照片
Photos from the county assessor's office
显示那里的地面上满是自行车的轮胎印
show bicycle tracks in the dirt all over the property.
非常感谢你  莱恩
Thank you very much, Ryan.
自行车轮胎印
Bike tracks.
金家外也有自行车印
There were bike tracks outside Kim's house.
爸爸  你知道这意味着什么吗
Dad, do you realize what this means?
意味着那晚金参加的派对就在那农房
That maybe the party Kim went to was at that farmhouse
而她看见有人在吸毒
and she saw kids doing meth.
不光吸毒  还制毒
Well, not just doing meth. Cooking meth.
所以她必须离开那里
That's why she had to get out of there.
所以她告诉莱尔她必须要作抉择
That's why she told Lyle she had some decisions to make.
她在考虑告发他们
She was thinking about turning them in.
那么有可能在她离开聚会之后
So maybe when she left the party...
某个参与制毒的人
One of our teenage meth cookers
担心她会报警
got worried she'd go to the cops.
-然后他就跟踪她  -骑着自行车
- So he went after her. - On his bike.
她房前的车胎印
The tire tracks at her house--
他知道她住在哪  因为他去过
He knew where she lived because he'd been there before.
他是跟金约会的男孩中的其中一个
He was one of the other guys Kim was seeing.
我们得跟金的母亲谈谈
We need to talk to Kim's mother.
好奇怪
Now that was weird.
异口同声是我和贝克特的专利
Usually I do that with Beckett.
你来这做什么
Hey, what are you doing here?
我
Hey. I, um...
只是想谢谢你对卡塞尔和
just wanted to... thank you for all of your help
阿丽克西斯的帮助
with Castle and Alexis.
这事打个电话不就得了
Seemed like you could have done that over the phone.
跟我说说吧  闺蜜
All right. Talk to me, girlfriend.
告诉我你在纠结什么
Tell me what's on your mind.
你觉得奇怪吗  这案子
Do you find it odd that alexis has gone
阿丽克西斯找了所有人帮忙  就是没找我
to everyone but me on this case?
她也没去找帕穆特
She hasn't gone to Perlmutter yet.
只要能不去没人愿意去的
Yeah, well, no one does if they can help it.
你不能把这当成是针对你的
Well, you can't take it personally.
我知道  只是
No, I know. It's just...
卡塞尔和我就要结婚了
Castle and I are about to become a family,
这本身就够不可思议了  然后
which is weird enough as it is, and...
他跟阿丽克西斯一起生活了很久
He and Alexis have this whole history
而那段生活我从未参与其中
that has nothing to do with me,
每当他俩之间有什么事情
And it kind of feels like when it comes to the two of them,
我总感觉像个局外人
I'm always gonna be on the outside.
家家有本难念的经
Perfect families don't exist.
这就要看你能否
It's gonna be up to you
找到一个切入点  融入他们
to find a way to make your baggage match their baggage.
要靠你自己来开始你们共同的生活
It's up to you to make your own history.
塔伯特夫人  很抱歉上门打扰
Mrs. Tolbert, we're very sorry to intrude.
你挺有胆量的
You have some nerve.
我知道你是谁  知道你想做什么
I know who you are, what you're trying to do.
听着  不管关于我们你听说了什么
Look, whatever you may have heard about us,
我们不是来跟你说弗兰克无辜的
We are not here to tell you that Frank henson is innocent.
我们只是想来问几个问题
We'd just like to ask you some questions.
除了你没人能回答的问题
Questions no one else can answer.
不然我们不会来打扰你的
Otherwise, we would not bother you.
什么问题
What questions?
金和她在约会的其他男孩有过矛盾吗
Did Kim have problems with any of the other guys she was seeing?
没别人了  就莱尔
There was no one else. Just Lyle.
而且刚和他分手
And she'd just broken off with him.
只是
Well, it's just that
我们听说有其他男孩去过她家
We had heard that some other boys had stopped by the house.
其他男孩  是的  她是名家教
Some boys? Yeah, she was a tutor.
一些学生觉得需要家教面子上过不去
Some of her students were embarrassed
她便悄悄地帮助他们
that they needed help, so she kept things quiet.
她就是这样一个好人
That's who she was.
你还记得那些学生的名字吗
Do you remember these students' names?
我才不会让你把这事扯到他们身上去
I'm not about to let you hang this on one of them.
-你们该走了  -多谢抽空
- Now you need to leave. - Thank you for your time.
女士  再多问一个问题
Oh, oh, madam, just one more question.
金是哪科的家教
What subject did Kim tutor?
化学
Chemistry.
-爸  -我知道  金是化学家教
- Dad... - I know. Kim tutored chemistry.
如果她的一个学生骗她
So what if one of her students tricked her
帮他学习如何制造病冰毒
into helping him learn how to cook meth?
当她发现了他的真正目的后
And when she figured out what he was doing,
她被灭口了
he killed her.
还有其他发现
No, there's something else.
当塔伯特夫人说出"化学"时
As soon as mrs. Tolbert said "Chemistry,"
我想起来了
I remembered.
看这个
Look at this.
犯罪现场发现了两本化学课本
Two identical chemistry books were found at the scene of the crime.
那么其中一本可能就是她学生的
So maybe the other one belonged to one of her students.
没错  但这种课本是很贵的
Right, but a textbook like this is expensive.
如果你弄丢了  你得付罚款
If you lost one, you'd have to pay a fine.
你会想把它找回来
You'd want it back.
除非它会把你与一场谋杀案联系起来
Unless it would implicate you in a murder.
爸  如果我们找到这本书是谁的
Dad, if we figure out whose book this is,
我们可能就找到了凶手
We might find our killer.
不知道这有没有可能
I don't know if that's possible.
我是说  毕竟这些书都是十五年前的了
I mean, these books are over 15 years old.
值得一试
It's worth a shot.
实际上  有些书都不止20年了
Actually, some of them are over 20 years old.
但由于预算削减  我们还在用它们
But because of budget cuts, we still use them.
你能找到1998年的记录吗
Can you pull up records all the way back to 1998?
就算我能  我大概也不应该
Well, even if I can, I probably shouldn't.
也许
Uh... perhaps
该给贵校购置新教材了
a generous donation for new textbooks is in order.
我想我能通融一下
I suppose I could bend the rules.
这是两本书的条形码
These are the barcodes from each book.
请填"现金"
Make it out to "Cash."
在哪呢  让我看看
Where are ya? Oh, let's see...
两本书在系统中都有记录
Both of them are actually still in our system.
1998年9月8号借出
Loaned out september 8th, 1998.
两本都没还回来
Neither was ever returned.
你能查到是谁借的这两本书吗
Any way you can figure out who they belonged to?
一本是金·塔伯特借的
Mm. One was Kim Tolbert's--
那个遇害的可怜女孩
the poor girl who died.
另一本呢
And the other one?
借书人叫约翰·汉森
Uh, looks like it belonged to one John Henson.
天啊
Oh, my god.
那是弗兰克的弟弟
That's Frank's younger brother.
这本化学书证明约翰到过金家
The chemistry book puts John in Kim's house,
但我们还需要更多证据
but we're gonna need a lot more than that
才能证明他就是凶手
to prove he's our killer.
这些资料都是关于弗兰克的
These files are all on Frank.
跟约翰有关的不多
There's not a lot here on John.
还要多久莱恩才能完成背景调查
How long until Ryan finishes his background check?
差不多该弄好了
He should be calling any minute.
你找到什么能把约翰和
Have you managed to find anything
谋杀案连起来的了吗
that might link John to the murder.
没  不过我确实发现了些
No, but I did find something
能把约翰和金连起来的事
that links John to Kim.
根据事故报告
According to this accident report,
97年弗兰克因超速卷入了一场车祸
Frank was speeding and got in a car crash in '97.
约翰当时和他在一起
John was with him.
他伤得挺重的
He was hurt pretty badly.
落下了很多课
He had to miss a lot of school.
他那学期正在修化学
He was taking chemistry that semester,
可能因此他需要金做家庭辅导
which is probably why he needed tutoring from Kim.
一定是莱恩
That'll be Ryan.
"约翰·汉森  无不良记录
"John Henson. Clean record.
未曾定罪  未曾被捕"  等下
No convictions, no arrests." Whoa, wait.
98年被捕一次  金被杀三个月前
One arrest in '98, 3 months before Kim was killed,
因持有管制品
for possession of a controlled substance.
冰毒吗
Meth?
没说明  起诉被撤销了
Doesn't say, and the charges were dropped,
但这说明约翰搞过毒品
but this establishes John was involved in drugs.
如果金向警方举报他制作冰毒
And if Kim had gone to the police saying he was a meth cooker,
他就不会受点小惩罚  蒙混过去
He wouldn't have gotten off with a slap on the wrist.
这就是杀人动机
That's motive for murder.
我们得跟约翰谈谈
We need to talk to John.
根据这份材料  他住在曼哈顿
According to this, he lives in Manhattan.
感谢你能来  汉森先生
Thank you for coming in, Mr. Henson.
只要能帮到弗兰克
Anything for Frank.
当然  这事上  他需要奇迹
Of course, at this point, he needs a miracle.
我一直都力挺我哥哥
I've always supported my brother.
从没想过他会伤害金
I never wanted to think he could have hurt Kim,
但如果是别人干的
but if someone else did this,
怎么会到现在还没发现呢
why haven't they been found by now?
也许所有人都找错了方向
Well, maybe no one was looking in the right place.
你跟金熟吗
Now how well did you know Kim?
我在学校每天都能见到她
Well, I saw her every day at school.
其他地方呢  下课之后
Anywhere else? Outside of class?
她家  有时候  她给我做家教
Her house, sometimes. She tutored me.
她遇害那天你在她家吗
And were you at her house the day that she died?
没有  为什么这么问
No. Why?
我们只是想知道
We were just wondering
你的化学课本怎么会在她家出现
what your chemistry book was doing at her house.
我肯定是把它落在那了  忘了
Well, I must have left it there... or forgot it.
而你从未想过要回来
And you never asked for it back?
金在学期期中遇害
I mean, Kim was killed somewhere in the middle of your school term.
你怎么会不需要那本书呢
Wouldn't you have needed it?
我也许买了本新的
Well, I might have bought a new one.
那是很久以前的事了
It was a long time ago.
我都记不得了
I don't really remember.
有什么关系吗
Why does that matter?
可能没什么关系
You know, it probably doesn't.
根据你的陈述
Now in your statement,
你说你在金被杀时待在自己的房间
You said you were in your room at the time of Kim's murder,
但你没有听到她的尖叫声
but you didn't hear her scream.
是的
That's right.
当晚你有没有听到其他不寻常的声音
Did you hear any other unusual sounds that night?
想不起来了
Uh, not that I can think of.
烟雾报警器的声音呢
What about the smoke alarm?
不  我听到了
Yeah, no, I did hear that.
弗兰克的审讯证词中
In Frank's trial testimony,
他没提到你去了车库
he never mentioned you coming down to the garage,
所以你在警报响起的时候一直待在房间里
so you were in your room the whole time the alarm was going off?
是的
Yes, I was.
我觉得这很奇怪  汉森先生
Now I find that odd, Mr. Henson,
因为安保公司记录显示警报持续了
because the security company logs show the alarm sounded
整整2分47秒
for a full two minutes and 47 seconds,
但你却一直待在房间里
but you stayed in your room that whole time.
没走出来查看一下
Never got up to check and make sure
屋子有没有烧着吗
that the house wasn't burning down?
你其实没有听到警报声吧
You never heard the alarm going off, did you?
因为你不在自己家里
Because you weren't in your house.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
是我杀了金  都是我做的吗
That I killed Kim, that I did it?
你那天晚上在哪里
Where were you that night?
我不会再回答你的任何问题
I'm not answering any more of your questions.
怎么回事  我以为一切都结束了
What is this, guys? I thought we were done.
汉森先生  我们找到了一些新证据
Mr. Henson, we've, uh, uncovered some new evidence--
证据显示杀害金·塔伯特的另有其人
evidence that suggests someone else killed Kim Tolbert.
谁
Who?
弗兰克  说出来可能不太容易接受
Frank, I know this is going to be hard to hear,
我们认为凶手可能是约翰
but we think it could be John.
不  约翰
No. John?
为什么这么说
Based on what?
他的化学书留在犯罪现场
His chemistry book was found at the crime scene.
金死时他的不在场证明不成立
His alibi for where he was when Kim died is falling apart.
你们他妈的是怎么回事
What the hell is wrong with you?
我说了让你们别管了
I told you to drop it.
这是什么意思
What do you mean?
弗兰克  我们真的查到东西了
Frank, we're really on to something.
我说了别查了
And I'm saying get off it.
你们别把约翰扯进来
You leave John out of this.
亲爱的  你怎么了
Honey, what's wrong with you?
如果是约翰做的
If John did this--
他知道
He knows.
他知道是约翰做的
He knows it was john.
弗兰克  是真的吗
Frank? Is this true?
你从头到尾都知道
You knew this whole time?
为什么要这么做
Why would you do this?
为什么要放弃自己的生命
Why would you throw your life away?
因为我放弃了他
Because I threw his away.
好吗
Okay?
他杀她是因我而起
I'm the reason why he killed her.
不  弗兰克  不论约翰做了什么  都不是你的错
No. Frank, whatever John did, it can't be your fault.
还记得我跟你说的那辆科迈罗吗
You remember that Camaro I was telling you about?
是我开的车
I rolled that car...
小强坐在里面
with Johnny in it.
我毫发无损
I walked away...
但他没有
But he didn't.
头部受伤后  他有一阵子没恢复过来
After the head injury, he wasn't right for a while.
他开始嗑药
He started taking drugs.
有了暴力倾向
He got violent.
他那段时间失忆了
He'd have these memory lapses.
不记得自己做了什么
He wouldn't remember what he did.
弗兰克
Frank.
当晚究竟发生了什么
What really happened that night?
我最担心的噩梦变成了现实
My worst nightmare came true.
现在好了
It's off now.
谢谢
Thank you.
天呐
Oh, my god.
你做了什么  约翰
What'd you do, John?
你做了什么
What'd you do?!
你得马上离开这里
You gotta get out of here.
听见了吗
You hear me?
回家
Go back to the house.
洗干净
Get cleaned up.
走  快点
Go! Now!
接下来警察就来了
The next thing I knew, the cops were there.
我能做什么呢
I mean... what was I supposed to do?
大家需要知道真相  弗兰克
People need to know, Frank.
不  他们不需要知道
No, they don't.
如果他们问我  我就否认
And if they ask me, I'm gonna deny it.
他们要处决你了
They're about to kill you.
我知道
I know.
你却听之任之  其实是约翰做的啊
And you're gonna let them, when it was John who did this.
玛吉  他记不得了
Maggie, he doesn't remember.
他来了这里三四次
It took three, four times of him coming here for me to realize
我意识到他一点都记不起那晚的事
that he--he doesn't remember anything from that night.
我想凭借某些法律依据免于刑罚
Look, I always hoped I'd get off on some kind of technicality, you know?
但不是这个
Not this.
不能这样
Never this.
他过上了新生活
He's built a life.
他有妻子
He's got a wife.
有两个孩子  我不能把这些从他身边夺走
He's got two kids, and I-I'm not gonna take that away from him.
弗兰克  求你
Frank, please...
对不起
I'm sorry.
只能这样了
This is the way it's gotta be.
我们一定还能做些什么
There must be something we can do.
弗兰克不想我们那么做
It's not what Frank wants.
但他是无辜的  爸爸  他就快要死了
But he's innocent, dad, and he's going to die.
明天
Tomorrow.
我知道
I know.
我都开始相信我们能救他了
I actually started believing we could save the guy.
我们几乎做到了
And we almost did.
我知道他有多爱玛吉
I know how much he loves Maggie.
如果他有时间再考虑考虑
If he just had more time to think about this,
可能就改变主意了
maybe he'd change his mind.
但没时间了
But the clock just ran out.
时间
The clock.
那通报警电话是什么时候
What time was that 9-1-1 call again?
邻居说是晚上8点04分听到尖叫声的
Uh, neighbor reported hearing the scream at 8:04 p.m.
怎么了
Why?
我们遗漏了一些东西  来看这张照片
We missed something. Come take a look at this photo.
这个墙面装饰是在打斗时掉下来的
This wall decoration could have fallen down during the struggle.
你是说这个太阳系小物件
You mean the solar system thingy?
不仅仅是太阳系小物件
Not just a solar system thingy.
太阳系的行星不会排列成这样
Our orbiting planets don't line up like that.
这是个二进制时钟
This is a binary clock.
这是钟
That's a clock?
是啊  金那样的理工女用的
Yeah. For science geeks like Kim.
数一下每个象限有几个行星
You count the amount of planets in each quadrant,
就能知道时间
it tells you the time.
这是7点32分
In this case, 7:32.
32分  那是报警电话半小时前啊
32? That's a half-hour before our 9-1-1 call.
那是因为弗兰克听到的尖叫声
That's because the scream that Frank heard
是8点04分约翰看到金的尸体时发出的
came from John we he discovered Kim's body at 8:04.
她已经死了半个小时了
She'd already been dead for 30 minutes.
兄弟俩都是无辜的
Both brothers are innocent.
我刚跟金的母亲通过电话
Hey. I just got off the phone with Kim's mom.
你打电话给金的母亲
Whoa. You called Kim's mom?
走投无路了嘛
Desperate times.
她没挂你电话吗
And she didn't hang up on you?
没有  她只是一直在吼
No. She mostly yelled.
她不肯告诉我金辅导过谁
She wouldn't tell me who Kim tutored,
但她说了金的所有家教收入
but she did say that all the checks
都存入了她的大学基金
Kim got from tutoring went into her college fund.
也就是说都是支票付款的
So she was paid by check.
这就表示可以查到谁付了钱给她
That means somewhere there's a record of who paid her.
没错  莱恩和埃斯波西托正在查银行记录
Mm-hmm. Ryan and Esposito are checking banks now.
这就是我们的突破点了  爸
This is it, dad.
绿碧树林  冰毒  还有那些单车轮胎印
Jasper Grove, meth, the bike tracks --
如果凶手不是弗兰克或是约翰的话
if it wasn't Frank or John,
那就肯定是其他那几个孩子的其中一个
it has to be one of those other kids.
你还在看那个录像吗
You still going through that video?
是啊  既然我们现在知道凶手不是弗兰克也不是约翰
Yeah. Now that we know neither Frank or John killed her,
那么我看这个录像的角度就完全不同了
this video plays very differently.
看这里
Watch this.
看到了吗
See that?
没有  你让我看什么
No. What?
弗兰克说他发现她的尸体在地上
Frank said he found her body on the floor.
他有提过他挪过尸体吗
Did he ever mention moving her?
没有
No.
据弗兰克所说  他只是拉走了约翰
According to Frank, he just pulled John away.
没错  扯断了吊坠手链
Exactly. Breaking the charm bracelet,
把吊坠弄了一地
spilling the charm all over the floor.
但是你看当验尸员小组
But watch as a medical examiner's team
第一次挪开她尸体的时候
moves her body for the first time.
看见了吗
See it now?
好像是她手链上的一个吊坠
It looks like another charm from her bracelet.
但是如果吊坠手链是在她死后才断的话
But if the charm bracelet broke after she died,
那这个吊坠又怎么会压在她的身下呢
how did the charm end up under her body?
卡塞尔  我们从实验室拿到证据箱了
Okay, Castle, we got the evidence box from the lab.
我们要找什么
What are we looking for?
证据记录单上写着里面应该有个证据袋  里面装着
Okay, the evidence log says there should be a bag containing charms
金断了的吊坠手链上的装饰物
from Kim's broken charm bracelet.
找到了
Got it.
其中一个吊坠应该是个海豚形状的
One of those charms should be shaped like a dolphin.
在呢
It's here.
手链应该也在里面
You should have the rope bracelet there, too.
把那个海豚吊坠串到绳子上
Thread that dolphin charm onto the bracelet.
好的  我正在串
Okay...I'm threading.
不行  串不上
Nope. Can't do it.
洞眼太小了
The hole's too small.
串不上
It doesn't fit.
那是因为这个吊坠根本就不是从金手链上掉下来的
That's because it didn't come from Kim's bracelet.
而是凶手留下的
It was left behind by our killer.
蕾妮  你能从那个吊坠上提取到DNA吗
Lanie, can you get D.N.A. off that charm?
也许吧  但除非你能找到与之匹配的DNA  不然没用
Maybe, but it won't help unless you have someone to match it to.
我们必须找出她在辅导谁
We need to know who she was tutoring.
你应该再给他们打个电话
You should call them again.
我20分钟前才刚给他们打过电话
I just called them 20 minutes ago.
我就不明白了  怎么要这么久呢
I don't understand. Why is it taking so long?
莱恩在几个小时前就查到金在哪开的户了
Ryan found the bank where Kim had her account hours ago.
那个账户早在98年就关闭了
The account was closed in '98.
从那以后那间银行搬迁了三次
The bank has moved three times since then.
他们可能没有保存那些文档
They may not have even kept the files.
万一他们没保存呢
And what if they didn't?
我们就快没时间了
We're running out of time.
我们得去见法官
We need to go to the judge.
空口无凭的去吗
With what?
弗兰克永远都不会承认他在保护约翰
Frank will never admit to covering for John.
那会导致他们发现约翰也在犯罪现场
That would put John at the crime scene.
那我们怎么办
So what do we do?
爸  告诉我该怎么办
Dad, tell me what to do!
我不知道
Hey, I don't know,
但不管发生什么事  我们都会一起面对
but whatever happens, we're gonna deal with it.
好吗
All right?
一起面对
Together.
生你气  我很抱歉
I'm sorry I was mad at you.
不  是我活该  对不起
Oh, no. I deserved it. I'm sorry.
喂
Yes?
名字是
What are the names?
雷恩警长
Chief Lane.
有什么可以为你们效劳的吗
Can I help you?
不  警长
No, chief.
但是我们可以为您效劳
But we can help you.
在金·塔伯特被害的当晚
This little dolphin pendant
证据科在她的客厅里发现了这个海豚吊坠
was found in Kim Tolbert's living room the night she died,
压在她的身下
underneath her body.
所以呢
So?
这不是她的
So it's not hers.
你们这些人真是不可理喻
You people are unbelievable.
雷恩警官  金去世的那年你多大
Officer Lane, how old were you when Kim died?
你说什么
Excuse me?
你跟她同班
You were in her class.
实际上  她还给你辅导过  对吧
In fact, she tutored you, didn't she?
你们到底想要说什么
What's this all about?
你给金·塔伯特开过支票  警长
Checks you wrote to Kim Tolbert, chief,
作为你儿子的辅导费
to pay for your son's tutoring.
他需要补习才能提高成绩
Needed some help keeping his grades up.
我打赌那是因为游泳队
Yeah, I bet because of swim team.
你们那年拿了州冠军
You guys took state that year.
那可是大新闻
It was big news.
泰迪  这到底是怎么回事
Teddy, what's going on here?
金·塔伯特被害当晚  她去过绿碧树林
The night Kim Tolbert was murdered, she was in Jasper Grove,
就在你在那年强行回收的一个农场附近
near a farmhouse you had foreclosed on a year earlier.
后来那房子被证实受到了
That house was later found to be contaminated
冰毒残留物的污染
with methamphetamine residue.
我们有理由相信你的儿子参与了制造冰毒
We believe your son was one of the people who contaminated it.
我们还有理由相信他之所以想要补习化学
We also believe he wanted to be tutored in chemistry
是为了学做冰毒
so he could learn how to cook meth.
这太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
但是金发现了你的秘密
But Kim caught on to you,
那对你们很不利
and that was bad for business.
所以当她离开那个派对时  你跟踪了她
So when she left that party, you followed her.
我们在她身上找到了硝酸铵
We found ammonium nitrate on her body.
我愿意打赌  在那间农场外面的
I'd be willing to bet that the tire treads
单车轮胎印  跟金遇害当晚
outside the farmhouse are going to be a match
在她家屋后找到的单车轮胎印将会匹配
to the bike treads behind Kim's house the night of her murder.
当然了  除此之外还有这个
And then, of course, there's that.
这对于法官来说已经是足够的间接证据了
Now that's enough circumstantial evidence for a judge...
但现在是2013年
but it's 2013.
我是说  我们现在可以提取降解的DNA
I mean, now we can even take degraded D.N.A.,
将其放大  测试
have it amplified, tested.
而且我肯定你们的证据存储科
And I'm sure that your evidence storage
完好的保留了你的海豚
has kept your dolphin well preserved.
泰迪
Teddy?
说话呀
Say something.
看着我
Look at me.
泰迪
Teddy!
鉴于大量的间接证据
Based on the overwhelming circumstantial evidence
和定罪后获取的
and the exculpatory results
DNA检验的辩护结果
obtained from post-conviction D.N.A. testing,
宾夕法尼亚联邦政府特此撤销
the commonwealth of Pennsylvania hereby vacates
对弗兰克林·托马斯·汉森的谋杀定罪
Franklin Thomas Henson's murder conviction
并免除他的所有罪行
and sanctions his exoneration.
我相信在此之前你已经
I'm sure you've spent far too many years
被法官高高在上地蔑视了太多年了
having judges look down on you,
所以这次我将会亲自从法官椅走下来
so I'll come down from the bench
并亲手将这份签署好的释放函交给你
and deliver the signed order of dismissal myself.
谢谢
Thank you.
我还以为是你干的
I thought it was you.
原来这么多年来  你一直在保护我
All this time, you were protecting me.
你怎么能原谅我呢
How can you ever forgive me?
原谅你
Ahh...forgive you?
我爱你
I love you.
我只想好好地过接下来的生活  弟弟
I'm just ready to live, brother.
你做的一切太出色了
What you did here was amazing.
谢谢
Thank you...
你所做的一切
for everything.
随时效劳
Anytime.
准备好回家了吗
You ready?
你不想留下来庆祝吗
Don't you want to stay and celebrate?
不想
No.
这就够了
This is enough.
再说  我还有一个人要感谢呢
Besides, there's someone else I need to thank.